

<articles>

	<article id="ax453"> 
	
		<title>Live as Long as an Olympian</title>

		<p>Olympic athletes are not like the rest of us. </p>
		
		<p>Most of them live longer, for one thing, as two revealing new studies found. But not
		all Olympians enjoy that bonus. Certain sports, the studies suggest, may be better than
		others when it comes to extending lifespan, a finding that has broad implications for
		those of us who have no expectations of ever being an Olympian.</p>
		
		<p>Scientists from Leiden University in the Netherlands found that "athletes from
		disciplines with moderate cardiovascular intensity or high cardiovascular intensity were
		similar," in terms of their lifespans, to "athletes from disciplines with low
		cardiovascular intensity."</p>
		
		<p>Cyclists, rowers, runners, cricketers and golfers who competed at the Olympics all
		enjoyed similar lifespans. But athletes from contact sports or sports that involved
		frequent crashes and collisions, like rugby and bobsledding, had shorter relative
		lifespans than the other Olympians.</p>
		
		<p>The study’s conclusion is heartening. "People tend to think the more the better when it
		comes to sports," says Frouke Engelaer, a doctoral candidate at the University of Leiden
		and a study co-author. "However, we have found that within a group of people who are fit
		already, this does not apply."</p>
		
		<p>High-intensity competitive activity was in fact no better than much less strenuous
		pursuits at increasing lifespans. </p>
		
		<p>"You don’t have to take the effort to do intense rowing," Mr. Engelaer said.
		"Low-intensity activities like walking and playing golf are just as good for your
		survival."</p>

	</article>

	<article id="bu153">
	
		<title>Flame-Retardant Chemical Lurks in Common Drinks</title>
	
		<p>Sarah Kavanagh and her little brother were looking forward to the bottles of Gatorade
		they had put in the refrigerator after playing outdoors one hot, humid afternoon last
		month in Hattiesburg, Miss.</p>
		
		<p>But before she took a sip, Sarah did what she often does and checked the label to see
		what products were in the drink. One ingredient, brominated vegetable oil, caught her eye.
		"I Googled it," Ms. Kavanagh said. "A page popped up with a long list of possible side
		effects, including neurological disorders and altered thyroid hormones. I didn’t expect
		that." The ingredient is comprised in part of bromine, which is found in brominated flame
		retardants, which are used to keep couches from catching on fire.</p>
		
		<p>She threw the product away and started a petition on Change.org, an online petition
		platform, that has almost 200,000 signatures. Ms. Kavanagh, 15, hopes her campaign will
		persuade PepsiCo, Gatorade’s maker, to consider changing the drink’s formulation.</p>
		
		<p>In fact, about 30% percent of drinks sold in the United States contain brominated
		vegetable oil, including Mountain Dew, also made by PepsiCo; Powerade, Fanta Orange and
		Fresca from Coca-Cola; and Squirt and Sunkist Peach Soda, made by the Dr. Pepper Snapple
		Group. Even some fruit juices contain the product. The ingredient is added often to citrus
		drinks to help keep the fruit flavoring evenly distributed; without it, the flavoring
		would separate.</p>
		
		<p>The European Union has long banned the substance from foods, requiring use of other
		ingredients, and Japan recently moved to do the same. But use of the substance in the
		United States has been debated for more than three decades, so Ms. Kavanagh’s campaign
		most likely is unrealistic.</p>
	
	
	</article>

	<article id="ps982">
	
		<title>Tending the Body’s Microbial Garden</title>
	
		<p>For a century, doctors have waged war against bacteria, using antibiotics as their
		weapons. But that relationship is changing as scientists become more familiar with the 100
		trillion microbes that call us home — collectively known as the microbiome.</p>
		
		<p>"I would like to lose the language of warfare," said Julie Segre, a senior investigator
		at the National Human Genome Research Institute. "It does a disservice to all the bacteria
		that have co-evolved with us and are maintaining the health of our bodies."</p>
		
		<p>This new approach to health is known as medical ecology. Rather than conducting
		indiscriminate slaughter, Dr. Segre and like-minded scientists want to be microbial
		wildlife managers. No one wants to abandon antibiotics outright. But by nurturing the
		invisible ecosystem in and on our bodies, doctors may be able to find other ways to fight
		infectious diseases, and with less harmful side effects. Tending the microbiome may also
		help in the treatment of disorders that may not seem to have anything to do with bacteria,
		including obesity and diabetes.</p>
		
		<p>"I cannot wait for this to become a big area of science," said Michael A. Fischbach, a
		microbiologist at the University of California, San Francisco. Judging from a flood of
		recent findings about our inner ecosystem, that appears to be happening. Last week, Dr.
		Segre and about 200 other scientists published the most ambitious survey of the human
		microbiome yet. Known as the Human Microbiome Project, it is based on examinations of 242
		healthy people tracked over two years. The scientists sequenced the genetic material of
		bacteria recovered from 15 or more sites on their subjects’ bodies, recovering more than
		five million genes.</p>
		
		<p>The project and other studies like it are revealing some of the ways in which our
		invisible residents shape our lives, from birth to death.</p>
		
	
	</article>

	<article id="axo12"> 
	
		<title>A Giant Tortoise’s Death Gives Extinction a Face</title>
	
		<p>Lonesome George is gone, and there will never be another like him.</p>
		
		<p>George, the last giant tortoise of his subspecies in this archipelago, was found dead
		in his corral at the Research Station here the morning of June 24 — to the shock of his
		devoted caretakers, who had hoped he would survive for decades to continue his line.</p>
		
		<p>The cause was natural, according to a necropsy, with the liver showing definite signs
		of aging. Giant tortoises can live well into their second century; George, who was brought
		here in 1972 from the northern island of Pinta, was thought to be around 100.</p>
		
		<p>The Galápagos is home to other types of giant tortoises, though their numbers remain
		low and their populations vulnerable. But in recent years, it was George who came to
		symbolize endangered species around the world, and he was enmeshed in the soul of the
		Galápagos — enshrined in stamps, logos and countless T-shirts.</p>
		
		<p>His loss has left the islands’ human inhabitants a bit bereft.</p>
		
		<p>"It is a very sad story for all of us," said Christian Saa, a national park ranger,
		guide and naturalist who had never been at the research center when George was not on
		hand. "We were expecting to have George another 50 years," he said as he stood before the
		pen, which houses a heart-shaped pool. "It feels kind of empty."</p>
		
		<p>George’s death was a singular moment, representing the extinction of a creature right
		before human eyes — not dinosaurs wiped out eons ago or animals consigned to oblivion by
		hunters who assumed there would always be more.</p>
	
	</article>
	
	<!--
		technology 1
		health 2
		science 3
	-->
	
	<!-- HEALTH -->
	<section type="health" num="2">
		<article id="hel11">
			<title>Laughter is the Best Form of Medicine</title>
		
			<p>Is laughter a kind of exercise? That offbeat question is at the heart of a new study of laughing and pain that emphasizes how unexpectedly entwined our bodies and emotions can be.</p>
			
			<p>For the study, which was published this year in Proceedings of the Royal Society B, researchers at Oxford University recruited a large group of undergraduate men and women. They then set out to make their volunteers laugh.</p>
			
			<p>Most of us probably think of laughter, if we think of it at all, as a response to something funny — as, in effect, an emotion.</p>
			
			<p>But laughter is fundamentally a physical action. "Laughter involves the repeated, forceful exhalation of breath from the lungs," says Robin Dunbar, a professor of evolutionary psychology at Oxford, who led the study. "The muscles of the diaphragm have to work very hard." We’ve all heard the phrase "laugh until it hurts," he points out. That pain isn’t metaphoric; prolonged laughing can be painful and exhausting.</p>
			
			<p>Rather like a difficult workout. But does laughter provide the health benefits of exercising?</p>
			
			<p>To find out, Dr. Dunbar and his colleagues had their volunteers watch, both alone and as part of a group, a series of short videos that were either comic or dryly factual documentaries. Then they measured how much pain the participants could stand. For the comical documentary viewers, their abdominal muscles were contracting, their endorphin levels were increasing in response, and their general sense of amiable enjoyment was on the rise. </p>
			
			<p>And what about pain? It turns out that pain thresholds went up after people watched the funny videos — but not after they viewed the factual documentaries.</p>
		</article>
		
		<article id="hel12">
			<title>Really? On a Cloudy Day, Your Eyes can Be Sunburned</title>
			<p>Recently, Anderson Cooper, a CNN anchor, described an unusual experience that left him temporarily blind. On an overcast day, Mr. Cooper, sans sunglasses, was filming a news segment on the water off the coast of Portugal. That night, he woke up feeling "like my eyes are on fire."</p>
	
			<p>"I douse my eyes with water," he said. "It turns out I have sunburned my eyeballs, and I go blind. I went blind for about 36 hours."</p>
			
			<p>What Mr. Cooper experienced, ophthalmologists say, was probably photokeratitis, also known as ultraviolet keratitis. It is essentially sunburn of the surface epithelium of the cornea, said Dr. Anne Sumers of Ridgewood Ophthalmology in New Jersey.</p>
			
			<p>Most people wear sunglasses on a sunny day. But even on an overcast day, UV rays can pass through clouds and damage your eyes. And not just at the beach. Like sand and water, fresh snow can also reflect UV rays on a cloudy day.</p>
			
			<p>One study in 2011 by the University of Utah found that of the documented cases of sunburned eyes at outdoor schools, most were of people who had not worn sunglasses. Even when individuals wore sunglasses, many cases occurred in people whose sunglasses lacked side shields. </p>
			
			<p>Surprisingly, however, many of the cases were in cloudy or low visibility conditions.</p>
			
			<p>Dr. Sumers said the condition is very painful, but typically heals with with medication. The bottom line is that sunburned eyes are more common than one would think. Even on overcast days, UV rays can pierce through clouds and cause serious eye damage. </p>
		</article>
	</section>
	
	<!-- SCIENCE -->
	<section type="science" num="3">
		<article id="sci11">
			<title>Telescope Detects Light From the Beginning of the Universe</title>
	
			<p>Ancient starlight, emitted by the first stars in the universe, has been detected using the Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope.</p>
			
			<p>Marco Ajello, an astrophysicist at the University of California, Berkeley, and his colleagues report the finding in the current issue of the journal Science. Dr. Ajello conducted the research while working at Stanford University.</p>
			
			<p>"These were probably the very first objects to form in our universe," he said. "They formed just about 500 million years after the Big Bang."</p>
			
			<p>Scientists suggest that the Big Bang occurred about 13 billion years ago, resulting in the creation of our universe, which continues to expand.</p>
			
			<p>The first stars in the universe were massive and primarily made up of hydrogen. They probably burned through the hydrogen quickly and exploded into supernovas early on. Although those original stars are long gone, the light from them is still traveling to us, Dr. Ajello said.</p>
			
			<p>Measuring the ancient starlight directly was impossible because the light from our own galaxy is overpowering. So instead, the researchers used gamma rays. For this, they relied on blazars, faraway galaxies that emit gamma rays."They are like lighthouses farther and farther away from us," Dr. Ajello said. "They are located at different distances from us, and from them we are able to measure the amount of starlight in different epochs."</p>
			
			<p>The researchers collected data on light in the universe 4 billion years, 8 billion years and 11 billion years after the Big Bang. In the future, Dr. Ajello hopes to take measurements at points even closer to the beginning of the universe.</p>
		</article>
		
		<article id="sci12">
			<title>Is American Science Falling Behind?</title>
		
			<p>Complaints and grim prognostications about the federal research budget are part of the background music of science. But are things getting worse in the United States </p>
	
			<p>American physicists are now rethinking how to carry out the famous neutrino experiment, which was to have been the centerpiece of a plan to convert the old 8,000-foot-deep Homestake gold mine in Lead, S.D., into a national laboratory for underground science.</p>
			
			<p>Similar facilities in Italy, Canada and Japan have become centers in the search for dark matter, neutrino experiments and other delicate work that requires shelter from cosmic rays. But in 2010, the National Science Foundation walked away from the $875 million project.</p>
			
			<p>Saul Perlmutter, of the University of California, Berkeley, said, “The danger, of course, is that we will watch the science (and scientists — and good students) move on to other countries and continents, where projects are being begun and completed.”</p>
			
			<p>With them, scientists say, could go the cultural excitement and innovative spark that invigorates the economy. The World Wide Web, for example, was invented at CERN, the European Organization for Nuclear Research (home to the world’s most powerful particle accelerator, the Large Hadron Collider), to help particle physicists communicate.</p>
			
			<p>By contrast, the United States’ flagship lab for high-energy physics, the Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory, known as Fermilab, had to close down last year due to funding. </p>
		</article>
	</section>
	
	<!-- TECHNOLOGY -->
	<section type="technology" num="1">
		<article id="tec11">
			<title>Digital Globes Offer a Dynamic Vision</title>
	
			<p>In the main hall of the hands-on exhibits at the Cape Town Science Center in South Africa, a lifeless, tattered globe stands under naked fluorescent bulbs, all but ignored by children passing through on school tours.</p>
			
			<p>Across a sunblasted courtyard and up a dingy staircase, another globe — a digital globe — stands in a darkened room. This globe is a shining sphere of light. Children stand awe-struck; adults of a certain age may be reminded of images like Apollo 8’s Earthrise photograph, while Tolkien fans of all ages will recall the spherical, swirling “palantír” of Saruman in “The Lord of the Rings” (forged in the days when Middle Earth was still flat).</p>
			
			<p>Until recently, cost and technical limitations have largely confined these modern spheres to institutional settings like science centers. But as technology improves and prices fall, it’s growing more likely that a digital orb will someday arrive in a classroom or boardroom — even a living room — near you.</p>
			
			<p>As the name suggests, a digital globe is a spherically shaped display screen. Like the old-school globes once common in classrooms, digital globes vary in size, but a typical model is about 24 inches across. Unlike the globes of your childhood, the image on a digital globe can be changed with the touch of a button. Controlled by a keyboard or tablet computer, a digital globe can toggle between familiar, static images, like the world’s political boundaries, topography or vegetation. It can animate complex phenomena, like the formation of weather systems, the effect of global warming on wolverine habitats or the annual pulse of sea ice. It can display the surface of the moon, the churning azure cloudscapes of Neptune or the celestial globe — the night sky.</p>
			
			<p>A digital globe can illuminate the human planet: wars, colonization, the formation of diaspora, modern trade flows or air traffic. It can also help teach math, play games, show movies or serve as a blank canvas for one’s inner, spherical artist.</p>
		</article>	
		 
		<article id="tec12">
			<title>Defense Secretary Warns of Dire Threat of Cyberattack on U.S.</title>
	
			<p>Defense Secretary Leon E. Panetta warned Thursday that the United States was facing the possibility of a "cyber-Pearl Harbor" and was increasingly vulnerable to foreign computer hackers who could dismantle the nation’s power grid, transportation system, financial networks and government.</p>
			
			<p>In a speech at the Intrepid Sea, Air and Space Museum in New York, Mr. Panetta painted a dire picture of how such an attack on the United States might unfold. He said he was reacting to increasing aggressiveness and technological advances by the nation’s adversaries, which officials identified as China, Russia, Iran and militant groups.</p>
			
			<p>"An aggressor nation or extremist group could use these kinds of cyber tools to gain control of critical switches," Mr. Panetta said. "They could derail passenger trains, or even more dangerous, derail passenger trains loaded with lethal chemicals. They could contaminate the water supply in major cities, or shut down the power grid across large parts of the country."</p>
			
			<p>Defense officials insisted that Mr. Panetta’s words were not hyperbole, and that he was responding to a recent wave of cyberattacks on large American financial institutions. He also cited an attack in August on the state oil company Saudi Aramco, which infected and made useless more than 30,000 computers.</p>
			
			<p>But Pentagon officials acknowledged that Mr. Panetta was also pushing for legislation on Capitol Hill. It would require new standards at critical private-sector infrastructure facilities — like power plants, water treatment facilities and gas pipelines — where a computer breach could cause significant casualties or economic damage.</p>
	
		</article>
	</section>	
</articles>