

<articles>

	<article id="ax453"> 
		<title>Mow Yard. Drop Off Kids. Take a Drive on Mars.</title>

		<p>PASADENA, Calif. — Matt Heverly, 36, started a recent workday as any young father
		might: up at 5:30, gulping coffee, fixing a bottle for the baby. He threw on jeans and a
		T-shirt and drove his two sons to day care. He stopped to get the brakes on his Toyota
		checked and swung by the bank.</p>
		
		<p>Then he went to the office ... to drive a $2.5 billion robot on Mars.</p>
		
		<p>Mr. Heverly leads a team of 16 drivers at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory here.
		Together, they are responsible for steering a six-wheeled, plutonium-powered rover called
		Curiosity across the Red Planet’s Gale Crater. Equipped with futuristic tools like a laser
		that can vaporize rock, the 2,000-pound robot arrived on Mars on Aug. 6, and Mr. Heverly
		took the wheel — or computer keyboard, actually — on Aug. 22.</p>
		
		<p>“Driving” a rover might be a misleading term. There is no joystick or accelerator, for
		a start. Mr. Heverly and his teammates tell the vehicle where to go next by entering
		hundreds of computer commands.</p>
		
		<p>Also, the driving is not done in real time: during the Martian night, the team plans
		where to send Curiosity next and sends instructions via radio transmission as the Mars day
		begins. Then the drivers go home, back to life on Earth, with all of its “don’t forget to
		take out the garbage” mundanity.</p>
		
		<p>“You have to try not to think about what’s happening out there, which is, of course,
		completely impossible,” Vandi Tompkins, 39, one of the drivers, said with caffeinated
		exuberance.</p> 

	</article>

	<article id="bu153"> 
	
		<title>Cancer Study Raises Hopes of Targeted Treatments</title>
	
		<p>The first large and comprehensive study of the genetics of a common lung cancer has
		found that more than half the tumors from that cancer have mutations that might be treated
		by new drugs that are currently in the pipeline.</p>
		
		<p>For the tens of thousands of Americans with that cancer — squamous cell lung cancer — the
		results are promising because they could foretell a new type of treatment in which drugs
		are tailored to match the genetic abnormality in each patient, researchers say.</p>
		
		<p>“This is a disease where there are no targeted therapies,” said Dr. Matthew Meyerson of
		the Dana-Farber Cancer Institute in Boston, referring to modern drugs that attack genetic
		abnormalities. He is a lead author of a paper on the study, with more than 300 authors,
		which was published online in the journal Nature on Sunday.</p>
		
		<p>The study is part of the Cancer Genome Atlas, a large project by the National Institutes
		of Health to examine genetic abnormalities in cancer. The study of squamous cell lung
		cancer is the second genetic analysis of a common cancer.</p>
		
		<p>“What we found will change the landscape for squamous cell carcinoma,” Dr. Meyerson said.
		“I think it gives hope to patients.”</p>
	
	
	</article>
	
	<article id="ps982">
			
		<title>Why Some Olympic Athletes Need to Gorge</title>
		
		<p>Endurance athletes, unlike the rest of us, have the unusual problem of having to work hard
		to keep weight on. “In your super-high-calorie-burning sports, like distance running,
		cycling or the triathlon, elite athletes can burn 15 or 20 calories a minute,” says Dr.
		Michael Joyner, a researcher at the Mayo Clinic in Rochester, Minn., who conducts studies
		of endurance athletes. At the peak of training, these athletes are working out four or
		five hours a day, he continues.</p>
		
		<p>These workouts can burn 4,000 to 6,000 calories, which “have to be replenished,” he
		continues, “if you want to train again the next day.”</p>
		
		<p>Refueling can resemble an episode of “Man v. Food,” with dinner consisting of things like
		a pound of pasta drizzled with olive oil (about 800 calories), a dozen eggs (840
		calories), an entire cheese pizza (perhaps 2,000 calories) and a pint of Ben &amp; Jerry’s
		cheesecake-brownie ice cream (1,000 calories). Plus beer (about 150 calories a bottle).</p>
		
		<p>One of the biggest issues, they told me, is that these athletes, in their quest for fuel,
		often turn to high-calorie but less nutritious processed foods — Snickers bars,
		store-bought chocolate-chip cookies, Pop-Tarts. Even an athlete who intends to eat
		healthfully can be defeated by nutritional realities. “You can only eat so much oatmeal
		and tofu,” Joyner says. A typical bowl of oatmeal contains about 150 calories, a cup of
		tofu about 175. You do the math.</p>
		
		<p>“Dietary fat provides nine calories per gram, whereas carbs provide about four per gram,”
		says Kerry Stewart, an exercise physiologist and a professor of medicine at Johns Hopkins
		University, meaning that fat is “energy dense” and desirable for famished athletes — but
		less so if you want to shed pounds. And even on a pizza-and-ice-cream diet, some athletes
		drop weight during peak training periods!</p>
		
	</article>	
		
	<article id="axo12">	
		<title>Panetta Warns of Dire Threat of Cyberattack on U.S.</title>
		
		<p>Defense Secretary Leon E. Panetta warned Thursday that the United States was facing the
		possibility of a “cyber-Pearl Harbor” and was increasingly vulnerable to foreign computer
		hackers who could dismantle the nation’s power grid, transportation system, financial
		networks and government.</p>
		
		<p>In a speech at the Intrepid Sea, Air and Space Museum in New York, Mr. Panetta painted a
		dire picture of how such an attack on the United States might unfold. He said he was
		reacting to increasing aggressiveness and technological advances by the nation’s
		adversaries, which officials identified as China, Russia, Iran and militant groups.</p>
		
		<p>“An aggressor nation or extremist group could use these kinds of cyber tools to gain
		control of critical switches,” Mr. Panetta said. “They could derail passenger trains, or
		even more dangerous, derail passenger trains loaded with lethal chemicals. They could
		contaminate the water supply in major cities, or shut down the power grid across large
		parts of the country.”</p>
		
		<p>Defense officials insisted that Mr. Panetta’s words were not hyperbole, and that he was
		responding to a recent wave of cyberattacks on large American financial institutions. He
		also cited an attack in August on the state oil company Saudi Aramco, which infected and
		made useless more than 30,000 computers.</p>
		
		<p>But Pentagon officials acknowledged that Mr. Panetta was also pushing for legislation on
		Capitol Hill. It would require new standards at critical private-sector infrastructure
		facilities — like power plants, water treatment facilities and gas pipelines — where a
		computer breach could cause significant casualties or economic damage.</p>

	</article>
</articles>